The Story of a Boy's Hunger
Toast is a drama, comedy, history film directed by S.J. Clarkson.
Young Nigel Slater has big culinary aspirations, even though
all his mother knows how to make is toast.
When his mother dies, relations grow strained between Nigel and his father, especially
when he remarries a woman who wins his heart with a lemon meringue pie.
Nigel enters culinary school, starts working in a pub, and finds himself competing with
his stepmother - both in the kitchen and for his father's attention.
Nigel Slater, played by Freddie Highmore.
Dad, played by Ken Stott.
Mum, played by Victoria Hamilton.
Young Nigel Slater, played by Oscar Kennedy.
Mrs Potter, played by Helena Bonham Carter.
Josh, played by Matthew McNulty.
Toast is a 2010 British biographical comedy-drama film based on the
autobiographical novel of the same name by the cookery writer Nigel Slater.
The film was directed by S.
Clarkson and written by Lee Hall.
The cast includes Freddie Highmore, Helena Bonham
Carter, Ken Stott and Oscar Kennedy.
It received a gala at the 2011 Berlin International Film Festival.
As a television film it was first broadcast on BBC One on 30 December 2010 and
was given a theatrical release in cinemas on 11 August 2011.
In 2018, it was adapted for stage by Henry Filloux-Bennett.
It first premiered at Week 53 Festival in March with a
subsequent run at the Edinburgh Festival Fringe.
In April 2019, it opened in London at The Other Palace.
The film explores themes of adolescence, cooking, nostalgia,
autobiography, based on memoir or autobiography.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.